Benjamin Hines

Email: <u>benjaminisaachines@gmail.com</u> Phone: 513-257-4118

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/benjaminisaachines/ GitHub: github.com/h1n3s1ght

Cyber Security | Application Engineer | Software Developer | Web Developer

SUMMARY

I am a quality-focused full-stack software engineer. Experiences from real-world applications and coursework from school strengthen my passion for software development and technology as a whole. My mission is to drive company and personal growth through strategically designed software deployments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Capstone Assignments General Assembly.

May 2022 – July 2022 Nashville, TN

Nashville, TN

- Produced (through the use of React.js, REST Node.js, and the entire MERN Stack) a fully functional full-stack vacation management application.
- Researched and programmed projects in Python's framework of Django in order to make user interaction with the product more conducive for growth.
- Coordinated and collaborated with four associates to design and implement an organizational tool to manage task priority.
- Deployed the GitHub repository from associates' collective works to an active and hosted IP address to fully deploy the developed software.
- Designed and programmed server code to correctly implement user database information to (the non-relational database) MongoDB using REST Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose.js, and full authentication/encryption with Bcrypt.js.
- Developed a JavaScript-based trip planning deployment that includes Bootstrap, jQuery, CSS, HTML, and API calls (through the use of AJAX).
- Explored and initiated a development from the Angular framework, Django server scripts, and PostgreSQL database to allow for efficient user interaction, server scripting, and data retention.

Technical Expert and Business Expert Apple Inc.

Oct 2015 – Current OH & TN

- Evaluated, debugged, and corrected over 10,000 unique technical issues.
- Identified inefficiencies in clients' software and hardware systems through dedicated and researched indepth technical deployment briefings.
- Integrated new Java-based Client Relationship Management (CRM) tools, Amazon Web Servers (AWS) Cloud Storage, and Ruby-on-Rails-based Web Applications into partner companies.
- Increased local business team's year-over-year sales by 30% by developing and fostering lasting new business-to-business connections.

Created growth within over 80% of our clients' businesses by deploying full-stack solutions such as;
Java-based POS (Square), Deluge-based Internal Communication Tools (ZoHo), and React-based Web Application Tools (Shopify).

Capstone Assignment Miami University

Aug 2016 – Dec 2019 Oxford, OH

- Designed and implemented custom illustrations into the JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL website production in the Computer Science (equivalent) program.
- Transformed and enhanced the nuanced changes of typography, shape, color, placement, alignment, use of white space, and many more to enhance UI for the UX on the platform.

Co-Founder & Operations Lead Fanvester

Apr 2016 – Nov 2016 Cincinnati, OH

- Adopted Agile methodology within the scrum team by utilizing third-party software such as Trello.
- Deployed REST, API, and PayPal Solutions into the company's online platform.
- Coordinated the development beta and A/B Testing of Fanvester's online platform.
- Implemented Google Analytics data to enhance user experience and retention.
- Acquired \$40,000 in funding through investor presentations demonstrating the company's mission and growth strategies.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive, Certification General Assembly (Software Engineering Bootcamp) July 2022 Nashville, TN

Interactive Media Studies, Bachelor's Degree Miami University (OH)

Dec 2019 Oxford, OH

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Dec 2021